ENRICO FASOLI



FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ABOUT

SUMMARY

☑ ENRICO.FASOLI1996 AT GMAIL

ENRICO.FASOLI1996 AT GMAI

C) FAZO96

in FAZO96

LANGUAGES

TYPESCRIPT
JAVASCRIPT/ES6

RUBY PHP

HTML

CSS

BACKEND

RAILS

NEXT.JS

NODE.JS

FRONTEND

REACT (WEB AND NATIVE)

VUE

WEBPACK+BABEL

DATABASES

SQL (POSTGRESQL PREFERRED) MONGODB

CLOUD

AWS (LAMBDA, S3, BEANSTALK, EC2, CLOUDFRONT)
HEROKU

DEVOPS

LINUX DOCKER BASH GIT Expert Full-Stack Software Engineer focused on SaaS Web Applications. I am a problem solver first, and I like being a major contributor or team leader and taking ownership of the codebase and product across the full technical stack.

EXPERIENCE

FLEXHIRE

10/2019 - PRESENT

TECH LEAD

Lead position in the tech team of the Flexhire SaaS platform, part of a small team

- Designed and directed the implementation of all technical work on the product
- Incrementally upgraded the tech stack of the product to the latest tech practices and to scale with the growing team and product scope
- Piloted adoption of Typescript and incrementally replaced the product's API with a type safe GraphQL API with real time capabilities, also used by Flexhire clients to integrate with our product
- Delivered substantial performance improvements while directing the transition from startup prototype to commercial product
- Upgraded and consolidated the Cloud Infrastructure systems of Flexhire using AWS tools
- Significantly enhanced monitoring, analytics, and backoffice capabilities of the platform
- Implemented horizontal scaling, infrastructure redundancy, and other fault prevention systems

FLEXHIRE

10/2018 - 10/2019

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Remote hourly contract position for development of the Flexhire SaaS platform, part of a small team

- Designed and directed the implementation of technical solutions to business problems, both backend and frontend
- Implemented end-to-end testing system for the SaaS platform

CHLU 11/2017 - 10/2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Part Time Remote hourly contract position, focused on directing the technical implementation of the Chlu protocol and applications

- Designed IPFS/libp2p based distributed systems running in the Browser through Websockets and WebRTC
- Managed the Open Source codebase of the Chlu platform

ESC 09/2016 - 01/2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Part Time permanent position, in a local company. Worked in a team of developers to deliver specialized applications to clients

- Worked Full Stack with PostgreSQL, PHP, Backbone.js, Marionette.js, Bootstrap
- Implemented and deployed custom management software following specifications from clients

EDUCATION

IIS GALILEO GALILEI CREMA